Hudson Shore Labor School Documents 5597
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Hudson Shore Labor School Documents
1947-1955
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Hudson Shore Labor School
Hill, James C
5597
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Consists primarily of memoranda and reports concerning the school's establishment and curricula in workers' education.
2298502
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 15, 2005
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 20, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1939 as the Bryn Mawr College Summer School for Women Workers in Industry, the Hudson Shore Labor School (HSLS) moved to its West Park, N.Y. location in 1949, expanding into an institute for training and development for workers and unionists.
Scope and Contents
Documents consist of memoranda and notes pertaining to workshops, training, budgets, curricula, faculty, labor history and workers' education; minutes and agenda of meetings of the faculty and Board of Trustees (1949-1951); annual reports of the Board of Trustees; reports and statements of the Rutgers Institute of Management and Industrial Relations regarding the curricula and programs offered at the HSLS; and faculty evaluations of training programs (1948-1951).
Also correspondence of L.H. Kerrison (Rutgers Institute of Management and Industrial Relations, faculty) with Helen D. Lockwood (HSLS trustee) on transferring HSLS workers' education sessions to Rutgers and of James C. Hill (Sarah Lawrence College, faculty) with Hilda W. Smith (HSLS trustee) on meetings and curricula. Additionally, press releases, bulletins, financial statements and pamphlets generated by and pertaining to the school's programs.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5703: James C. Hill Additional Files
Adult education teachers -- Training of -- United States; Adult education; Adult education teachers; Workers' education -- New Jersey -- Curricula; Workers' education -- United States; Hill, James C., 1914-; Kerrison, Irvine L. H. (Irvine Ledward Hamilton), 1916-; Lockwood, Helen D.; Smith, Hilda (Hilda Worthington); Hudson Shore Labor School; Rutgers University. Institute of Management and Industrial Relations
2298502
- Board of Trustees and Joint Executive and Planning Committee Meeting Minutes, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Board of Trustees and Joint Executive and Planning Committee Meeting Minutes, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Board of Trustees and Advisory Committee Minutes, Summer Workshop in Workers' Education Methods and Techniques, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Board Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondents include James (Jim) Hill, Margaret D. Wood, Rhetta M. Arter, Hilda Smith, Helen Lockwood, and others.
- Board Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Correspondents include Helen D. Lockwood, Ernestine L. Friedmann, James C. Hill, Louise H. Gallop, and others.
- Board Correspondence, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Correspondents include James (Jim) C. Hill, Helen Lockwood, Ernestine Friedmann, Rhetta Arter, and others.
- Financial Data, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Pamphlets, Newsletters, Publications, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Includes "Each Man is An Island" by John Caswell Smith, Jr., Quotations and Readings in Labor History, and Hudson Shore Labor School 1948 Yearbook.
- Flyers and Publications, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Includes Hudson Shore Labor School: Democracy in Action and Hudson Shore Labor School: Institute in Workers Education Training.
- Training and Workshop Publications, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Includes Workers' Education Methods materials and flyer for "Awake and Sing!" by Clifford Odets.
- Board of Trustees Info; Faculty & Student Lists, 1948-1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Session Info; Training Programs, Releases, Reports, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Evaluations & Questionnaires; Info of Hudson Shore School, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Photos, Notes, Songs, etc., 1948-1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)